Hello everyone welcome back to our channel
Vimshasha today we will discuss about
ICICI Pidencal Life Insurance from the financial services sector in the stock market,
it is a large cap company and a
profitable company where we
can trust this company and some brokerage houses have
also given targets so we will discuss that also further, there will be
complete detailed analysis
about this share so guys now
watch the entire video till the end so that all the
information reaches you in a proper way
and at which levels you have bought this share,
please comment on that also.
So now let us see
how much the institution has reduced or
increased its stake quarter on
quarter.  It is a private sector company
where promoters hold 72.88%
stake in this company
and where promoters have
reduced their stake by 0.05% quarter on
quarter.  Foreign institutions have
reduced their stake by 1.67%.  And domestic
institutions have also reduced their stake by
0.20%.
But mutual funds have
increased their stake significantly to 1.96%.
Means promoters, domestic
institutions and foreign institutions have
reduced their stake.  And mutual
funds have increased their stake on a quarterly
basis.  So if this stock
is in your portfolio then you can stay invested
for the long term.  And yes friends, if
you find this video even a little bit innovative
and you like it, then please do subscribe to the channel.
So let's start
without any delay.  This company was started
in July 200.
This company is 26 years old.  Means has a lot of experience
in this sector.  Let us see what is the business model of the company.
This company
provides life insurance, pension
and health insurance.  So
from the financial services sector, you
can keep ICICI PUL on your radar.  And now let's come to the
company's data.  This company was listed
in September 2016 at a price of ₹310 and
now the stock is trading around ₹600.
So first of all let us see
how much return ICICI Prudential has given
to its investors so far.  If we look at the returns of 1 year, then
this stock has given a return of 10%
and in 5 years this stock has
given a return of 30%.  And when we
look at the all time returns, this stock has given a
return of 93%.  Meaning, if someone had
invested only Rs 1020 in 2016, then the
value of his Rs 10,000 today would have been
around Rs 19,000.  This means that this stock has
generated decent returns for its investors
in the long term.  Now let's come to the second
part.  Let us see how strong the fundamentals of the company are.  The
market
cap is around Rs 870 crore.  The PE
ratio is 63.59.  End industry PE
is 12.52.  This means that Industry P is trading at an expensive valuation at S.  The
end book
value is 92.  This means the stock is trading at a
six times multiple of its book value.
And in front of this,
this share is at a face value of Rs 10.  So now the question
arises guys, is this stock undervalued
or overvalued right now?  ICICI PDL is 35 to
40% overvalued as of today and the
company had made a profit of around Rs 1186 crore in the last financial year.
Means
is a profitable company no doubt.  So now let us
look at the share levels.  The stock
is currently trading around 600.  Its 52
week high was 706 and 52 week low was
around 525.  This means the stock has corrected almost 15% from its 52-week high.
Means a
healthy correction guys you can consider it.  But
still, if you see this stock around 500 and 550, then
you can consider it a buying opportunity.  So these are all the
details of the company, at what valuation is this share
trading right now, this
data is given on S.  So now let us see
what target the brokerage has given for ICICI PNL.
Firstera Capital has given buy rating on January 22 with a
target of Rs 730.
Minsara Capital believes that this stock can
show an upside of around 21%.  Second,
IDBI Capital has given buy rating on March 9
for a target of Rs 715.  Means ADBI
Capital believes that this stock can
show you an upside of around 19%.  And the
third one guy Motilal Oswal has
given buy rating on recent 9th March
for target of 800.  Means Motilal Oswal
believes that this stock can show an upside of around 33%.
So, based on the data on S, we
understand that brokerage houses and
mutual funds are quite bullish on this stock.
So you can also keep this stock on your radar.
And even with every 8% fall, you
can also think of doing SIP.  And yes
friends, if you make any investment
then please definitely take advice from your advisor.
And most importantly, do your own research.
And I hope guys you
liked this information.  So see you
in the next video.  Take care of yourself.  B
positive.  Jai Hind Guys.